<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Neorotribe</title>
    <link href="https://www.neorotribe.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://www.neorotribe.com" />
    <updated>1970-01-01T10:00:00+10:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>June Ong</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://www.neorotribe.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Love Yourself</title>
        <author>
            <name>June Ong</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.neorotribe.com/love-yourself.html"/>
        <id>https://www.neorotribe.com/love-yourself.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-02T16:19:47+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/19/8e5ec0f44081928206f772a278baa745.jpg" alt="" />
                    I just can't believe the year is coming to a close. I came across a saying that "Sorrow is better than happiness because it has a refining influence" on us. Do you agree? Safe to say, the whole world is in this together. The Covid&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/19/8e5ec0f44081928206f772a278baa745.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>I just can't believe the year is coming to a close. I came across a saying that "Sorrow is better than happiness because it has a refining influence" on us. Do you agree?</p>
<p>Safe to say, the whole world is in this together. The Covid situation has been a real mammoth of a crisis this year. Personally, we had many challenges as this crisis is just hallmarked with unpredictability and uncertainties. As a normal human being, we thrive on predictability and we are creatures of habits. Yet the crisis has stripped it off completely. Liam had a hard time and it spillover to the rest of us. </p>
<p>But looking back, the crisis has helped me see clearly what are the essentials to life. It is a giant reset button pressed on all my priorities. Yes it is important to have your basics covered like a roof over your head and food on the table. Having said that, what truly stands out for me this period is giving love to oneself and others. To love yourself is an art. It is cultivated through time and habit. It is having the wisdom to say no and yes at the right time. To love yourself is the greatest thing you can do for your family. </p>
<p>In this age we are living, we are torn from all corners, demanding our attention and hearts. Sometimes, we fail to be kind to ourselves. I learnt that no one will do that for me except for myself. When I set aside time to care for myself, I am whole to care for my family, kids and friends so on.</p>
<p>This is my biggest takeback from this year. I am extremely grateful to have my family in lockdown with me. At then end of the day, love is the only currency that will stand the test of life. Love yourself, and love others.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>School&#x27;s Out, Holiday&#x27;s in!</title>
        <author>
            <name>June Ong</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.neorotribe.com/spring-break-ideas.html"/>
        <id>https://www.neorotribe.com/spring-break-ideas.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-02T16:19:47+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/16/IMG_8174.PNG" alt="" />
                    My school kids are officially going on their Spring break holidays tomorrow. In their head, they are going for a holiday. And their idea of a holiday is staying in a fancy hotel watching TV (Because we doesn't have a TV in our home remember?).
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/16/IMG_8174.PNG" alt="" />
                <p>My school kids are officially going on their Spring break holidays tomorrow. In their head, they are going for a holiday. And their idea of a holiday is staying in a fancy hotel watching TV (Because we doesn't have a TV in our home remember?). </p>
<p>I have been checking out Airbnb and accommodations for the past 2 weeks. Last year this time we were in Myola Jervis Bay, it was unforgettable. It certainly feels like a long time ago with all the Covid drama dragging out this year. Anyway, if you have done the same thing as me, you would soon realise that every accommodation up North and down South has been fully booked. Strangely, there are more options left in Sydney City. I guessed everyone just want to get out for abit.</p>
<p>Anyway, I have done some research and planning. For us, what works is getting out of home. A change of environment is good and we come back appreciating the comfort of our own home. Being out takes my focus and stress of keeping the house in order. </p>
<p>So there you go, 10 day trip ideas for Spring Break Holidays 2020. </p>
<div class="gallery-wrapper"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-columns="3">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/16/gallery/IMG_0638.jpg" data-size="3024x4032"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/16/gallery/IMG_0638-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="1024"></a>
<figcaption>Liam</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/16/gallery/IMG_0637.jpg" data-size="3024x4032"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/16/gallery/IMG_0637-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="1024"></a>
<figcaption>Levi</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/16/gallery/IMG_0640.jpg" data-size="3024x4032"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/16/gallery/IMG_0640-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="1024"></a>
<figcaption>Lily</figcaption>
</figure>
</div></div>
<p>1) Balmoral Beach, Mosman</p>
<p>Apart from Nicole Kidman frequently sighted there, we have found ourselves going back to Balmoral Beach again and again. It's the calm gentle waves the kids love. Invest in a good cabana, some beach chairs, pack a picnic and you are set to have the best day with your kids there. There's stuffs to do for young to the older kids. I have seen the older kids jumping off the jetty and it looks really fun.</p>
<p>2) <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://www.earlystartdiscoveryspace.edu.au/">Early Start Discovery Centre, University of Wollonggong</a></p>
<p>It is about 1.5 hour drive away from Sydney CBD. We were so impressed by the set up of the whole centre that we were honestly considering moving to Wolloggong for it. We spent the whole day there on our last trip and there was just endless stations of educational fun for all my kids. We held a year of membership for the whole family and it was worth our every cent of money. More on membership <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://www.earlystartdiscoveryspace.edu.au/visit/membership/">here</a>.</p>
<p>3) <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://www.treetops.com.au/">Treetop Adventure Park</a></p>
<p>We have gone to the location at Hills for twice now. Our first was on a Saturday dewy morning in Winter and second was to Liam's classmate birthday. It does require focus, coordination and certainly courage whenever they have to jump off the flying fox. I am looking forward to take Lily after she turns 3. Having all 3 kids on the obstacle course building their confidence is very fulfilling and relaxing for me. </p>
<p>4) <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://www.hornsby.nsw.gov.au/lifestyle/sports-and-recreation/parks-and-playgrounds/fagan-park">Fagan Park</a></p>
<p>We have gone to Fagan twice and we never quite been able to comb through the whole area. They have a great playground by the carpark and my kids love to ride their scooters on the trails around it. </p>
<p>5) <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://www.icentralcoast.com/somersby-falls.html">Somersby Falls</a></p>
<p>My good friend Sarah has been talking about Somersby Falls. I have yet to check it out but looking at the pictures, it is defo worth a visit. It will be on my to-do list this holidays.</p>
<p>6) <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://www.visitnsw.com/destinations/south-coast/jervis-bay-and-shoalhaven/huskisson/attractions/moona-moona-beach">Moona Moona Creek, Huskisson</a></p>
<p>Moona Moona Creek is a piece of paradise in South Coast of Sydney, Jervis Bay. It reminded me alot of Maldives' crystal clear water. We spent the whole day there and left the place very tanned and happy. This is one of the rare time I could not resist jumping into the water with the kids (Usually I just like to laze by the shore and leave the playing to Brandon ha).</p>
<p>7) Byron Bay</p>
<p>I have never been to Byron Bay but I have heard amazing stuffs about it. Apart from the fact that Chris Hemsworth and his massive estate, I read that Zac Efron has recently relocated there. There must be something about Byron Bay that has drawn the Hollywood celebrities to make it their home. We have yet stretched our stamina to driving 12 hours for a roadtrip but would keen to check out Byron Bay this year.</p>
<p>8) Canberra, ACT</p>
<p>Singaporeans would be very familiar with Canberra as the High Commission of Singapore is there. It is where we collect our Singapore passports. I do enjoy how sparse the city is. There are heaps of things for kids to do there. Questacon, Cockington Green Gardens, National Dinosaur Museum and our recent favourite is the National Arboretum Pod Playground. </p>
<p>9) Bilpin, NSW</p>
<p>Whenever I think about Bilpin, I would remember the daytrip where we brought my dad there. We meant to bring him to fruit-picking but the orchard was closed that day. We had a good time nonethless eating the famous Bilpin Apple Pie, visiting <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://bilpincider.com/">Bilpin Cider</a> and taking lots of photos. </p>
<p>10) Wisemen's Ferry</p>
<p>Wiseman’s Ferry is the oldest ferry crossing still in operation in New South Wales. It is our first time driving onto a ferry, and crossing the river. As the whole area is surrounded by National Parks, you can imagine how beautiful it is. There is something very rustic and inviting when you step foot beyond the ferry port. Definitely worth a day trip. Grab a lunch at Spencer Village Store, it is a quaint little town with friendly locals who treats you family and they serve a mean burger and coffee. </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Sydney Hills Horse Riding Centre</title>
        <author>
            <name>June Ong</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.neorotribe.com/sydney-hills-horse-riding-centre.html"/>
        <id>https://www.neorotribe.com/sydney-hills-horse-riding-centre.html</id>
            <category term="Reviews"/>

        <updated>2020-11-02T16:19:47+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/IMG_9003.jpeg" alt="" />
                    Staying in the Hills has worked out really well for us. We are close to every possible option of outdoor activity. I have often meet parents who either has horses as pets or their kids riding as a hobby. There is also much traction on&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/IMG_9003.jpeg" alt="" />
                <p>Staying in the Hills has worked out really well for us. We are close to every possible option of outdoor activity. I have often meet parents who either has horses as pets or their kids riding as a hobby. There is also much traction on equine therapy, how horses are used as a form of therapy for autistic children. </p>
<p>The funny thing is, Brandon was nearly killed by a horse. When he was 14, a horse riding accident left him hanging for life at the edge of a cliff in a quarry. That's heaps of drama within a sentence. I carried the perspective of how a horse can be erratic and dangerous from his experience. </p>
<p>But you know me, I have to be convinced with my own experience. I never settled with a hearsay. Our belief as parents is to allow our children to grow from different kind of experiences. So getting our kids to take up horse riding is an inevitable thing. I am also secretly hoping through the kids, Brandon would find closure with his traumatic incident.</p>
<p>We booked in a 30 mins session for Lily. We were told that children grow with the horses. Lily was very easy and engaging. She was given a crash course on brushing and saddling Cloud, the shetland pony. It was more on getting Lily to be comfortable around him. I was a little concerned with Lily's eczema flare up as Cloud was massively shedding. But Lily was alright for the day. Apparently horses grow thick coats during Winter and shed them coming Spring and Summer. How amazing is nature.</p>
<div class="gallery-wrapper"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-columns="2">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/gallery/IMG_8984.jpeg" data-size="3024x4032"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/gallery/IMG_8984-thumbnail.jpeg" alt="" width="768" height="1024"></a>
<figcaption>Lily bringing the reins</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/gallery/Lily-Cloud.jpg" data-size="3024x4032"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/gallery/Lily-Cloud-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="1024"></a>
<figcaption>Getting acquainted with Cloud</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/gallery/IMG_8986.jpeg" data-size="3024x4032"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/gallery/IMG_8986-thumbnail.jpeg" alt="" width="768" height="1024"></a>
<figcaption>Safety comes first</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/gallery/IMG_8988.jpeg" data-size="3024x4032"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/gallery/IMG_8988-thumbnail.jpeg" alt="" width="768" height="1024"></a>
<figcaption>Getting ready to hop on</figcaption>
</figure>
</div></div>
<p>The owner Carolyn took over the second half of the lesson. We saddled Lily on Cloud and went for a ride around the vicinity. Lily was taught how to move and stop Cloud. I must say for a 30 mins lesson, it was ample for Lily to gain a good experience with horse riding. She was really exhausted by the end of it. We were quite happy with how it all turned out. </p>
<figure class="post__image" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/Lily-Horse-Riding.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/responsive/Lily-Horse-Riding-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/responsive/Lily-Horse-Riding-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/responsive/Lily-Horse-Riding-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/responsive/Lily-Horse-Riding-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/responsive/Lily-Horse-Riding-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/15/responsive/Lily-Horse-Riding-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="Lily enjoying a trot" width="800" height="600">
<figcaption >Lily enjoying a trot with Cloud</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>We have signed both Liam and Levi for their <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://www.sydneyhillshorseriding.com/school-holiday-camps">holiday camps</a> coming in Oct. It would be really interested to see how it would pen out for Liam because he can not tolerate strong smell. Perhaps the calming effect or a budding love for a horse could help him overcome his sensory irregularities. </p>
<p>Sydney Hills Horse Riding Centre is in the midst of getting approval to become an NDIS provider. This is a piece of good news as this would mean special needs family in Hills District would enjoy the close proximity to the centre. </p>
<p>What I love about them is their horses enjoy 2-3 days of break in the week. This commitment of caring for their horses would definitely transcend in the service and work they do. This is something we want to instil in our children, caring for their environment, nature and animals. </p>
<hr>
<p>Sydney Hills Horse Riding Centre</p>
<div id="1125808489" class="u_1125808489 sectionContactBox">
<div>Address: 66 Kenthurst Road</div>
<div>Dural, 2158</div>
<div>NSW, Australia </div>
<div>Phone: 0421 218983</div>
<div> </div>
<div> </div>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Our journey with Autism (Part 2)</title>
        <author>
            <name>June Ong</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.neorotribe.com/our-journey-with-autism-part-2.html"/>
        <id>https://www.neorotribe.com/our-journey-with-autism-part-2.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-02T16:19:47+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/13/Screen-Shot-2020-09-23-at-4.45.33-pm.png" alt="" />
                    I didn't know how strong I was until I was faced with the desperate situation of Liam's autism. It is almost like going on an auto-pilot mode. The mum's instinct to protect and fight for her child. Looking back, those early years were a blur.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/13/Screen-Shot-2020-09-23-at-4.45.33-pm.png" alt="" />
                <p>I didn't know how strong I was until I was faced with the desperate situation of Liam's autism. It is almost like going on an auto-pilot mode. The mum's instinct to protect and fight for her child. </p>
<p>Looking back, those early years were a blur. They consist of intensive therapies, fingers crossing, huge disappointments but celebrations of little successes. If you ask me, I have become a better person in every way through the curve that was thrown at me. It has taught me patience, persistence, love, forgiveness and basically every difficult form of traits that one would rather not acquire. </p>
<p>I want to speak to the special needs parents specifically about forgiving yourself. I carried the guilt for a long time. The nudging feeling of guilt and self-blame. I was convinced Liam was autistic because I painted the house and inhaled the paint fumes (How ridiculous). I later on met an anti-vaxer lady that told me vaccinations causes autism and it is a conspiracy by the Australian government (Man that was an eventful day I never saw her again). </p>
<p>Does it matter really if we find out the reason why our child has autism? We will still love them and would fight for them. I have to forgive myself, for not doing enough, for doing too much, for being tired, for resenting, for wanting a normal family, for losing hope, for the past, for the present and for what is to come. </p>
<p>When we forgive ourselves, we allow hope to fill our hearts and this gives us energy for the future to fight. Self-care is not selfish, it is the highest form of love we can offer to ourselves and our family.</p>
<p>May you be kind to yourself today x</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Our journey with Autism (Part 1)</title>
        <author>
            <name>June Ong</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.neorotribe.com/our-journey-with-autism-part-1.html"/>
        <id>https://www.neorotribe.com/our-journey-with-autism-part-1.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-02T16:19:47+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/12/Screen-Shot-2020-09-23-at-4.45.33-pm.png" alt="" />
                    This will be the first of many posts which I will talk about our journey with autism. I will include our experiences in dealing with the landscape of both Singapore and Australia's special needs support. I hoped this series of posts on our experiences would&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/12/Screen-Shot-2020-09-23-at-4.45.33-pm.png" alt="" />
                <figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/12/Screen-Shot-2020-09-23-at-4.45.33-pm-2.png" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/12/responsive/Screen-Shot-2020-09-23-at-4.45.33-pm-2-xs.png 300w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/12/responsive/Screen-Shot-2020-09-23-at-4.45.33-pm-2-sm.png 480w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/12/responsive/Screen-Shot-2020-09-23-at-4.45.33-pm-2-md.png 768w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/12/responsive/Screen-Shot-2020-09-23-at-4.45.33-pm-2-lg.png 1024w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/12/responsive/Screen-Shot-2020-09-23-at-4.45.33-pm-2-xl.png 1360w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/12/responsive/Screen-Shot-2020-09-23-at-4.45.33-pm-2-2xl.png 1600w"  alt="" width="792" height="441"></figure>
<p>This will be the first of many posts which I will talk about our journey with autism. I will include our experiences in dealing with the landscape of both Singapore and Australia's special needs support. I hoped this series of posts on our experiences would shine a light on autism and be helpful in some ways.</p>
<p>I am careful to talk about Liam as I do not want to invade into his privacy or overstep his consent. My concern is not to leave any permanent digital footprint about him without him truly understanding the ramifications of it. Having to say that, I am happy to take it offline with any parents should you have any similar concern about your child. </p>
<p>I have had a normal and healthy pregnancy. If anything I gained too much weight. I was an oversized dinosaur waddling when I was into my 3rd trimester. The delivery was long but it was alright. I have filled up hundreds of forms regarding Liam's diagnosis and they always ask similar questions if the pregnancy and delivery were normal.</p>
<p>Liam was a happy baby and toddler. He has had developmental delays but we chalked it to the fact that boys usually develop later than girls. When he was 2, he started to have uncontrollable meltdowns. Looking back, it was a combination of the fact that he wasn't able to express himself (as he was non-verbal at the time), and he wasn't able to cope with the sensory overloads. We were really helpless and isolated because in the asian culture, there is a strong stigma of having a child with mental disability. </p>
<p>He was diagnosed when he was 4. We waited 1.5 year for early intervention support but it was taking too long for us. We were not equipped to help him and our daily life was beyond stressful. We tried 2 preschools and they could not cope with him. Those were really dark days because nothing we do seems to help him at all. It was very stressful in Singapore because we find that there was a lack of empathy and understanding at that point. This was about 6 years ago. I would like to to believe Singapore has progressed in this aspect. </p>
<p>The turning point truly came for us when we relocated to Sydney, Australia. We received funding for his therapy from the government and there were endless options of support for his well-being here. I had to change my perspective from having no support to picking the suitable one for him. We had an intensive year of therapies ranging from psychology, behavioural, speech and occupational. They were essential to help him to be independent and cope with life. </p>
<p>He has come on leaps and bounds. We have had many people who told us that they cannot tell that Liam has autism. I am not so sure about that statement. Autism is an invisible disability. It can actually work for and against him. I will elaborate on this on my following posts.</p>
<p>Singapore parents who are struggling with their children on the autism spectrum and finding it difficult in Singapore, please do not think that relocating to other countries is the only solution. The whole world has moved into teleconferencing and online communication due to Covid. You can access to any training or therapy not limited to what Singapore provides. Moreover, it is about finding the right therapy, providing a safe and consistent environment for your child. As parents progress, children progresses too. </p>
<p>I am including some objective helpful readings if you suspect your child has autism. I can't stress enough how important it is not to get into non-mainstream ideas like curing autism through diet, being anti-vax and so on. Don't be taken on a ride. They usually sell you the idea of hope. Accept your child for who he or she is. This is the first step to finding light at the end of the tunnel.</p>
<p>Please reach out and I will be happy to give more information from our experiences.</p>
<p>Sending you light and love x</p>
<hr>
<p>For Sydney residents:</p>
<p><a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://www.autismspectrum.org.au/">Autism Aspect Australia</a></p>
<p><a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://www.autismcommunity.org.au/">Autism Community Network</a></p>
<p>For Singapore residents:</p>
<p><a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://www.autism.org.sg/">Autism Resource Centre</a></p>
<p><a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://www.babybonus.msf.gov.sg/parentingresources/web/Special-Needs/Well-Being/Diagnosis/Specialneeds_ASD_Signs?_afrLoop=41912155462590900&amp;_afrWindowMode=0&amp;_afrWindowId=null#%40%3F_afrWindowId%3Dnull%26_afrLoop%3D41912155462590900%26_afrWindowMode%3D0%26_adf.ctrl-state%3Dnksrws8s9_4">MSF - Early Signs of ASD</a></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Vtech Kidizoom Duo Camera</title>
        <author>
            <name>June Ong</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.neorotribe.com/vtech-kidizoom-duo-camera.html"/>
        <id>https://www.neorotribe.com/vtech-kidizoom-duo-camera.html</id>
            <category term="Reviews"/>

        <updated>2020-11-02T16:19:47+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/11/Lily-Kidizoom.jpg" alt="" />
                     Lily received her first birthday present this year from her Grandma in Singapore. She asked for a pink camera because she loves pink for everything and she was coveting after Levi's camera for a while now. We combed through the web and realised Vtech&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/11/Lily-Kidizoom.jpg" alt="" />
                <figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/11/Lily-Kidizoom-jpg.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/11/responsive/Lily-Kidizoom-jpg-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/11/responsive/Lily-Kidizoom-jpg-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/11/responsive/Lily-Kidizoom-jpg-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/11/responsive/Lily-Kidizoom-jpg-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/11/responsive/Lily-Kidizoom-jpg-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/11/responsive/Lily-Kidizoom-jpg-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="450" height="600"></figure><br>Lily received her first birthday present this year from her Grandma in Singapore. She asked for a pink camera because she loves pink for everything and she was coveting after Levi's camera for a while now.</p>
<p>We combed through the web and realised Vtech Kidizoom Duo Camera has received raving reviews above the rest. It is on the pricier side but we wanted to get something that is durable and educational. Vtech has a good reputation of creating toys that has educational value. We have had their toys for both the boys before and they played with them for a long time. </p>
<p>The camera has a front and rear photo-taking function. It is up to date for the selfies-wefies generation. It has built-in auto-flash, large colour screen, 4x digital zoom and also voice recorder with voice changing effects and built-in games. The games were something I wasn't keen on. Lily tried to play with them but she was too young for it. She ended up throwing a tantrum which was too familiar in my household. My kids has a bad rep of throwing tantrums over screens, ipads and technology. </p>
<p>I wasn't keen on Lily or the boys hogging on the camera for the games. The problem with my kids at the moment is once they get on the screen, they get stimulated to the point where any other activity seems boring to them. So I just didn't want to dig myself another hole. </p>
<p>Anyway, Brandon discovered that the games can be disabled. So it comes with parental control for that. Well done VTech, for considering the luddites mum like me.</p>
<p>We disabled the game function and let the kids use the camera as it is. And Lily has used it to take many unflattering photos of me, which I will spare you the agony of them.</p>
<p>Overall, it is a good buy and investment. It is a good present for kids as well. It is recommended for ages 3-9 so I can see it being used across my kids who happens to be age 3, 6 and 9. </p>
<hr>
<p>For more information on Vtech Kidizoom products, please click <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://www.vtech.com.au/product/search/_/kidizoom">here</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Custom Cubbys &amp; Tee Pees</title>
        <author>
            <name>June Ong</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.neorotribe.com/custom-cubbys-and-tee-pees.html"/>
        <id>https://www.neorotribe.com/custom-cubbys-and-tee-pees.html</id>
            <category term="Reviews"/>

        <updated>2020-11-02T16:19:47+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/159C985B-F274-4B62-9920-064C0CCBCCA4-3.JPG" alt="" />
                     When we moved into our current home years ago, the previous owner left behind a timber playset. It was perfect for the 3 kids then. They were aged 1, 4 and 7. The kids were on it every single day. As the kids grow,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/159C985B-F274-4B62-9920-064C0CCBCCA4-3.JPG" alt="" />
                <figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/DSC4402-2.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/responsive/DSC4402-2-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/responsive/DSC4402-2-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/responsive/DSC4402-2-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/responsive/DSC4402-2-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/responsive/DSC4402-2-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/responsive/DSC4402-2-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="600" height="400"></figure><br>When we moved into our current home years ago, the previous owner left behind a timber playset. It was perfect for the 3 kids then. They were aged 1, 4 and 7. The kids were on it every single day.</p>
<p>As the kids grow, we realised they were growing out of the playset. They were bored with it. Eventually they were doing dangerous stunts on it, climbing on top of the roof and doing silly things. Liam was very fixated on the idea of a treehouse ever since Brandon shared with him on how he always wanted one growing up. Having a space for Liam to reset his sensory challenges has always been an essential for him too. </p>
<p>I started researching on the possibility of having a treehouse. But we don't have a tree! Seems pretty unusual because Sydney homes usually have a few at their front or backyards. In Liam's usual fashion, he asked me to grow a tree for it. His mind has no concept on limits. So the next thing was getting a cubby. Most flat packed cubbies are good for toddlers and young kids. Their entry usually would not exceed 1.2m. So our first priority is to have a cubby that would suit them for years, not just at their current age. </p>
<p>I understand there's a cost involved in having a big investment. So we did it the Neo's way. We saved for it. Our home only consists of legos (mostly given or hand-me-downs), and books. We do not purchase toys which always go into landfills anyway. Our previous big purchase was the trampoline and the kids goes on it every single day.</p>
<p>After almost 6 months of researching and correspondences with different cubby companies in Australia, we finally decided on Custom Cubbys &amp; Tee Pees. It was a thoroughly good experience dealing with owners Darren and Renee. Nothing was too much of a hassle for them. They answered every query I had promptly and professionally. We had to use a freight company as their company was based in Victoria. <br><br></p>
<div class="gallery-wrapper"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-columns="2">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/gallery/15.jpg" data-size="960x720"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/gallery/15-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="576"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/gallery/17.jpg" data-size="960x720"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/gallery/17-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="576"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/gallery/37.jpg" data-size="960x720"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/gallery/37-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="576"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/gallery/38.jpg" data-size="960x720"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/10/gallery/38-thumbnail.jpg" alt="" width="768" height="576"></a></figure>
</div></div>
<p>We were kept abreast on the progress of the cubby. The mark of a good company is when owners take pride in what they do. They made sure we levelled the ground properly on our end before the cubby came. It was a smooth process for us even though the cubby was coming from interstate and we had to install it on our own. </p>
<p>We chose a white fibreglass slide and coordinate the cubby colors based on our home's. It is a visual goal that we will evict the kids eventually to the cubby. </p>
<p>We will not hesitate to recommend Darren and Renee for their professionalism, workmanshop and heart in what they do. </p>
<hr>
<p>Photo by Eric Yip @ https://eyxl.com.au/</p>
<p>Contact Info:</p>
<address>Phone: 0419 331 243</address><address>Email: customcubbys@bigpond.com</address><address><a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://www.facebook.com/customcubbys01/">Facebook</a> <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://www.instagram.com/customcubbys_and_teepees/">Instagram</a></address>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Coffee Trad3rs</title>
        <author>
            <name>June Ong</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.neorotribe.com/review-coffee-trad3rs.html"/>
        <id>https://www.neorotribe.com/review-coffee-trad3rs.html</id>
            <category term="Reviews"/>

        <updated>2020-11-02T16:19:47+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/8/104912272_153488076286811_3186643407877911592_n.jpg" alt="" />
                     Our good friend has recommended Coffee Trad3rs to us sometimes back. The owner, James, a Taiwanese has a wealth of experience in the cafe industry. His previous stint was in Malaysia helping a friend to set up a cafe. We decided to hit the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/8/104912272_153488076286811_3186643407877911592_n.jpg" alt="" />
                <figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/8/96723089_730455787758541_7912899674283217704_n1.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/8/responsive/96723089_730455787758541_7912899674283217704_n1-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/8/responsive/96723089_730455787758541_7912899674283217704_n1-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/8/responsive/96723089_730455787758541_7912899674283217704_n1-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/8/responsive/96723089_730455787758541_7912899674283217704_n1-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/8/responsive/96723089_730455787758541_7912899674283217704_n1-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/8/responsive/96723089_730455787758541_7912899674283217704_n1-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="800" height="600"></figure><br>Our good friend has recommended Coffee Trad3rs to us sometimes back. The owner, James, a Taiwanese has a wealth of experience in the cafe industry. His previous stint was in Malaysia helping a friend to set up a cafe. </p>
<p>We decided to hit the cafe during Father's Day weekend. To be honest, we weren't sure about moving to Hills District but we have been pleasantly surprised by the community so far. There is a good mix of nature and shopping districts littered everywhere. People are alot laid back here, and always happy to strike up a convo. </p>
<p>Upon entering the cafe, you would be overwhelmed by the number of indoor plants who are thriving and happy. James is the main vibe of the cafe. He is chirpy, loud and engaging. You could see straightaway that he is gifted to do this.</p>
<p>The coffee and food were phenomenal. There was a Father's Day special, pork knuckle. I wasn't keen on the meat so I devoured the rest of the vegetables. Every single dish tasted differently and you could tell care and thought were put into preparing them. </p>
<p>We had the 3 kids with us and it is always a challenge to keep them occupied. Levi would get bored very easily and he would lead the pack to be silly. We have to juggle to keep them seated and happy before they embark on this slippery road of no return (Pun intended). There were so many times we have to leave and return home. Stories for another day.</p>
<p>James was very attentive and kept coming back to the table to engage the kids. He promised them ice-cream (The cafe has their own gelato chest!). Mind you, it was a full house indoor and outdoor. James was not just interested to earn your bucks, he was about heart and making friendship. We left the place with our hearts full that day. </p>
<p>You can't counterfeit heart and sincerity in doing business. People can tell. </p>
<p>Anyway, it is definitely worth a visit if you are in the area. Good coffee and good food. The setting is serene if it's not busy but buzzing with life it is. Look out for James, he might give you a gelato.</p>
<hr><address>Coffee Traders<br>Shop 1 / 8 Victoria Avenue,<br>Castle Hill, NSW</address><address>Mon-Fri: 6am – 4pm<br>Sat: 7:30am – 3:30pm<br>Sun: Closed</address><address> </address><address><a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://thecoffeetraders.com.au/">Website</a> <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://www.instagram.com/coffeetrad3rs/">Instagram</a> <a href="#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://www.facebook.com/coffeetrad3rs/">Facebook</a></address>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Who Are We</title>
        <author>
            <name>June Ong</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.neorotribe.com/who-are-we.html"/>
        <id>https://www.neorotribe.com/who-are-we.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-02T16:19:47+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/7/110246741_1669651189865509_6728060733868684083_n.jpg" alt="" />
                    We are Neorotribe. We are a tribe of 2 parents and 3 beautiful children. Our family name is Neo. You would have guessed by now. Dad is Brandon. Mum is June. Follow by firstborn Liam who is beautiful, kind, unassuming and just so happens to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/7/110246741_1669651189865509_6728060733868684083_n.jpg" alt="" />
                <p>We are Neorotribe. We are a tribe of 2 parents and 3 beautiful children. Our family name is Neo. You would have guessed by now.<br><br>Dad is Brandon. Mum is June. Follow by firstborn Liam who is beautiful, kind, unassuming and just so happens to have autism. Second-born Levi is sensitive, free-spirited and marked by his grandma's dimples. And lastly, the princess of our tribe Lily is endearing in every way. <br><br>We are from Singapore and have made Sydney Australia our home since 2016. The journey here has been amazing and challenging at the same time. We have been broken and healed, inundated by our experiences. Nonetheless, we would like to think there are also interesting and funny experiences that are worth sharing. We hoped you would be enriched and inspired by our stories.</p>
<p>Don't be a stranger and say hello below.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Taronga Zoo</title>
        <author>
            <name>June Ong</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://www.neorotribe.com/taronga-zoo.html"/>
        <id>https://www.neorotribe.com/taronga-zoo.html</id>

        <updated>2020-11-02T16:19:47+11:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/6/Taronga-2.jpg" alt="" />
                     Everytime we visit Taronga Zoo, our experience is always different, in a good way. The view of the harbour would almost always guarantee a mood lift. Today we got there around lunch time. Kids were excited as usual. They are pretty straight forward, they&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/6/Taronga-2.jpg" alt="" />
                <figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/6/Taronga.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 48em) 100vw, 768px" srcset="https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/6/responsive/Taronga-xs.jpg 300w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/6/responsive/Taronga-sm.jpg 480w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/6/responsive/Taronga-md.jpg 768w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/6/responsive/Taronga-lg.jpg 1024w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/6/responsive/Taronga-xl.jpg 1360w ,https://www.neorotribe.com/media/posts/6/responsive/Taronga-2xl.jpg 1600w"  alt="" width="800" height="600"></figure><br>Everytime we visit Taronga Zoo, our experience is always different, in a good way. The view of the harbour would almost always guarantee a mood lift. Today we got there around lunch time. Kids were excited as usual. They are pretty straight forward, they are happy when they get to go free range. </p>
<p>I was just a little nervous when we saw the line to the seal show. It was a massive queue and there weren't much social distancing. We made our way against the traffic of people and made a beeline to the playground. I think any person that has gone to Taronga enough with food can tell you the resident turkeys there are relentless. They are really aggressive and no longer afraid of humans. The whole stress about guarding your children's food became like a chore really. We ended up force-feeding our children at double the speed while wary-eyed of the turkeys the whole time. I supposed tourists would find this fascinating and wouldn't mind the experience of kookaburras swopping down on your fish-and-chips or turkeys ransacking your snackbag. </p>
<p>And a heads up, the usual main restaurant near the elephant enclosure is open for takeaway but not for sit down dining. BYOF. And maybe a red hot chilli and feed it to the turkey when it gets too annoying (I am kidding!). </p>
<p>If you fancy a good exercise, you will work your glutes in the zoo walking up and down the slopes. It is especially intense on the way out to the exit. This is why I got my 9 yo Liam to push the stroller up today. Return of Investment. HA HA.</p>
<p>I still think the zoo is a relatively safe place for a family day out in regards to the Covid situation. There are plenty of greens and spots for a sit down picnic. Some animals enclosures are pretty small and it does get a little crowded for my liking. But as parents it is on us to practice common sense and remind our kids about keeping their distance and maintaining their hygiene. </p>
<p>Taronga Zoo also made provision for the autism community. Guests with autism and their family and friends get to enjoy early entry to the zoo on select days in the year. There is also an option of the zoo team providing extra assistance should there be a need. Read more <a href="https://www.neorotribe.com/taronga-zoo.html#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://taronga.org.au/sydney-zoo/visitor-information/autism-services">here</a>.</p>
<p>Due to the current COVID-19 safety restrictions, all visitors are required to purchase tickets online (with up to 20% savings online!) and attend the Zoo on their selected date only. Tickets will not be available for purchase at the gate. If you plan to visit Taronga Zoo this season, you are advised to <a href="https://www.neorotribe.com/taronga-zoo.html#INTERNAL_LINK#/post/null" title="https://au.openforms.com/Form/3dc5a1e9-a4f7-45f9-8153-ded980312be4">book online</a> prior to attending. This is to prevent overcrowding and ensure social distancing measures can be effective. </p>
<p>Enjoy your Taronga Zoo visit!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
